dmexco.com 2019-10-23

# Privacy Policy - DMEXCO

### Privacy Policy

 **Welcome to our DMEXCO website – we’re glad you’re here!**

Like all websites, our site collects personal data from our visitors.

The protection and security of your data are important to us, and our website complies with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG). Below you can read about what data we use during your visit, why we might pass these data along, and, if so, to whom.

You can either read the entire Privacy Statement or – with the help of the overview – click areas of interest to select them.

### 1\. Controller within the meaning of the GDPR:

a. The controller within the meaning of the laws for the protection of privacy is:

Koelnmesse GmbH  
Messeplatz 1  
50679 Cologne  
Germany

b. Data Protection Officer:

If you have any questions regarding the handling of your personal data or wish to exercise your rights as a data subject, you are welcome to contact our Data Protection Officer:

Koelnmesse GmbH  
Messeplatz 1  
50679 Cologne  
Germany  
E-Mail: [datenschutz-km@koelnmesse.de ](mailto:datenschutz-km@koelnmesse.de)

### 2\. Which personal data are processed?

“Personal data” within the meaning of this Privacy Policy are disclosures about your personal or factual circumstances. These include things such as your name, date of birth, your E-Mail address, address and telephone number.

But personal data also include information that is automatically collected about the use of our website (known as “access data”). In addition to the access data, we will process personal data only if you voluntarily provide it to us, e.g. in the context of a registration, contact request or newsletter subscription, or when ordering tickets. Personal data will be used only to the extent required and only for such purposes as you have approved and/or as are permissible under law.

### 2.1 Collection of access data

For technical reasons, whenever you access our website, your terminal automatically transmits data: The following data are stored separately from other data that you may transmit to us:

  * date, time and duration of your visit to our website
  * IP address
  * the website visited
  * the user tool (i.e. web browser, operating system) you used to access the website
  * the action carried out on our website
  * the search terms entered in the search engines and in the site search, as well as the search result
  * whether the access attempt was successful or not
  * information retrieved incl. downloads
  * the server from which you come and the website through which you arrived at the current website

We store these data in log files and delete them after 14 days. The data contained in the log files are be stored separately from your other data.

Storage for periods longer than this occurs only in individual cases (e.g. in case of suspicion of abuse or fraud). In these cases, the respective log files are stored until the facts have been clarified and any subsequent measures required have been completed.

For technical reasons, we require the access data to display the website to you, and to ensure stability and security. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR, since we have a legitimate interest in offering you our services in a technically flawless, secure and optimized manner.

To provide our website and the services associated with it, we rely on service providers that process your data as set forth in this Privacy Policy exclusively on our behalf and according to our instructions (known as “processors” pursuant to Article 28 GDPR). These include:

  * Website hosting service provider: PlusServer GmbH
  * Service provider for operation of the ticket shop: dimedis GmbH
  * Service provider for integration of the press box function: Press 1 – HighText Verlag Graf and Treplin OHG
  * Service provider for integration of videos: GoEssential Inc.
  * Service provider for the exhibitor directory: Corussoft GmbH
  * Service provider for conference management: hubb.me
  * Service provider for surveys: SurveyMonkey Europe UC
  * Service provider for link shorteners: Rebrandly (Radiate Capital Limited)

### 2.2 Ticket shop

Our events are limited to trade visitors. To purchase a ticket through our ticket shop, you must provide us with different kinds of data. The following disclosures are mandatory:

  * Name
  * Company name
  * Company address (city, street address, postal code, country)
  * Position
  * E-Mail address
  * Marketing attributes
  * Password

These data are required to set up and manage a user account for you. We also need this data in order to verify your status as a trade visitor and to be able to put you in touch with suitable exhibitors or contact persons as part of our matchmaking service. Not least, we need these data to respond to any inquiries you may have.

We process these data in order to be able to provide you with the services of our ticket shop and to fulfill any contracts concluded with you, as set forth in Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR. Data are also processed to promote our events and services (on the basis of Section 7 (3) of the German Unfair Competition Act [UWG]), for optimization purposes and for market and opinion research.

As part of your registration or profile, you can also provide the following voluntary information:

  * Academic title
  * Additional title
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * URL

This information is voluntary and not required to purchase a ticket.

These personal data are only processed based on your explicit consent, Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR.

### 2.3 Networking function (DMEXCO app)

Our app offers a networking feature you can use to interact with fellow users.

When information sharing is approved, you can use the networking features to get in contact directly with fellow app users. The app distinguishes between “public participants” in the event and “trade visitors”. This distinction is relevant to whether and when the respective contact within the network directory is available for you to contact using the networking function.

  * “ **Public participants** ” are (i.) the persons designated by the respective exhibitor and those (ii.) who provide a certain service within the framework of an agreement with Koelnmesse, such as speaker or facilitator. These persons are basically available for the networking function in the context of fulfilling the contract.
  * “ **Trade visitors** ” are the visitors to our event. These persons are included in the networking directory if (i.) the network function was already approved during ticket purchase or (ii.) consent was declared within the app at some later point in time in the People section or in the Networking area. The prerequisite for this is the purchase of a DMEXCO ticket.”

As a result, what this means is that all exhibitors, speakers and facilitators are available to you for the networking function, as are all trade visitors who have purchased a ticket and consented to participate in networking.

With the networking function, you can:

  * view and find all public and (consenting) trade visitors to the event
  * contact other (consenting) participants (“Say hello…”)
  * accept contact requests without restriction (“Let’s talk”)
  * accept contact requests to a limited extent (“I’ll call you”)
  * view incoming and outgoing contact requests (grouped by status) at a glance
  * compare contacts on my smartphone with (approved) participants
  * scan other participants’ contact details using their badge
  * manage all collected contacts in a single overview

We would like to point out that, depending on the preferences you have set, these areas may be publicly accessible, and that any personal information you post or provide during registration may be viewed by others.

We cannot control how other users of our app or website use this information. Specifically, we cannot prevent unwanted messages from being sent to you. Content uploaded to community areas can be stored indefinitely. If at any time you wish to remove any content you have posted, please send us an e-mail to this effect to the following address:  
[info@dmexco.com](mailto:info@dmexco.com).

We collect all the data entered as part of the community functions in order to be able to provide you with the community functions as intended, Art. 6 (1) (a) and (b) GDPR.

You will find more information in the You can find more information in the Privacy Statement for our DMEXCO app.

### 2.4 Contact

You may contact us by phone or E-mail. The data processing that occurs when you contact us can be performed for different purposes, depending on the nature the concern expressed in your content. As a rule, we store and process the data provided so that we can process the matter for which you contacted us. Your data are also stored and processed in a CRM (customer relationship management) system. We currently use software by Hubspot for this purpose. The legal basis for this use of your personal data is provided under Article 6 (1) (1) (f) GDPR.

However, if the content of your message serves to execute a contractual relationship between us, we will base the processing of your data on Article 6 (1) (1) (b) GDPR.

Provided there are no legal retention obligations that prevent us from erasing the data processed in connection with contacting us, we will erase these data as soon as we no longer require them.

### 2.5 Registering as an exhibitor or speaker

You can register as an exhibitor or speaker on our website. We process the personal data with which you provide us via the input screen for this purpose.

Your personal data are processed to initiate, execute and settle a corresponding relationship of trust, Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR.

Specifically, we process your personal data for the following purposes:

  * Purchasing tickets to our events;
  * Redeeming vouchers;
  * “One-click” registration of future tickets;
  * Delivery and payment of other Koelnmesse offers (e.g. trade fair directories and catalogs);
  * Review of trade visitors’ characteristics;
  * Announcements, technical information and other materials for events of interest to you;
  * Offers of individually tailored service offerings;
  * Invitations to take part in our market and opinion research;
  * Prevention or detection of abuse and fraud, particularly in the case of vouchers and free tickets;
  * Simple updating of your personal data online, if necessary.

In addition, from a marketing point of view, the following:

  * Sending of individual e-mails by a sales representative
  * Sending of marketing e-mails, e.g. about the sale of additional and promotional services such as advertising space, etc.
  * Survey requests
  * Sending of newsletters and mailings

From a speaker’s point of view:

  * Redeeming ticket vouchers
  * Inclusion in the website
  * Inclusion in the Conference Guide (agenda)
  * Announcements of speaker slots via social media, newsletters and other media
  * for all speaker-related mailings, such as: Briefings, VIP events and VIP services

Data collected later are also assigned to the customer account. This includes e.g. data collected when a ticket is ordered.

### 2.6 Registering as a visitor

You can register as a visitor on our website or the Koelnmesse website. We process the personal data with which you provide us via the registration screen for this purpose.

Your personal data are processed to initiate, execute and settle the corresponding license agreement, Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR.

You can visit DMEXCO without registering online. You can also purchase an anonymous ticket at the ticket desks on site without registering.

Unfortunately, we cannot provide you with services such as online advance sales or simplified repeat ticket purchase, matchmaking, travel services or other services unless you register with us.

Specifically, we process your personal data for the following purposes:

  * Purchasing tickets to our events;
  * Redeeming vouchers;
  * “One-click” registration of future tickets;
  * Delivery and payment of other Koelnmesse offers (e.g. trade fair directories and catalogs);
  * Review of trade visitors’ characteristics;
  * Announcements, technical information and other materials for events of interest to you;
  * Offers of individually tailored service offerings;
  * Invitations to take part in our market and opinion research;
  * Prevention or detection of abuse and fraud, particularly in the case of vouchers and free tickets;
  * Simple updating of your personal data online, if necessary.

Data collected later are also assigned to the customer account. This includes e.g. data collected when a ticket is ordered.

If you decide to purchase a ticket, we will process your name along with your address and contact details, together with the contract and payment data (e.g. account details) you have provided. The legal basis for this use of your data is provided in connection with contractual performance (Article 6 (1) (1) (b) GDPR). The data are passed on to third parties for payment processing by providers of financial services, and to government authorities and consultants as permissible under law.

If you want to erase your user account along with your data, then send us an e-mail to this effect addressed to [info@dmexco.com](mailto:info@dmexco.com). We will comply with your request if it does not involve data we are required to store under commercial and tax law (as these data are subject to continued storage under Article 6 (1) (1) (c) GDPR).

### 2.7 Newsletter

You have the opportunity to subscribe to newsletters free of charge. When you subscribe to the newsletter, the data are transmitted to us from the input screen. We also collect data on the IP address and the time of registration as proof of your consent to receive the newsletter.

To prevent abuse, first you will receive an e-mail with a confirmation link that you must then activate in order to receive the actual newsletter (known as a “double-opt-in” procedure).

As part of the registration process, your consent to the processing of data is obtained, and reference is made to this Privacy Statement. The basis in law for the processing of data is thus Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR. Because we have to record your e-mail address to deliver the newsletter, this is a mandatory disclosure. You are not required to indicate whether you are here as a visitor, exhibitor, speaker or media representative. We use this information to provide you with targeted content in the medium and long term.

As part of the registration process, your consent to the processing of data is obtained, and reference is made to this Privacy Statement. The basis in law for the processing of data is thus Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR. Your e-mail address is recorded to permit delivery of the newsletter. The question of whether you are a visitor, an exhibitor, a speaker or a media representative is designed to permit us to offer you targeted content.

Your data will be stored as long as your subscription to the newsletter remains active. Naturally, you can cancel the newsletter at any time. A link for this purpose can be found in every newsletter. Alternatively, you can send an informal message to this effect to [info@dmexco.com](mailto:info@dmexco.com).

We reserve the right to send you information by e-mail on goods and services similar to those you have purchased from us in application of Section 7 (3) of the German Unfair Competition Act [UWG]. You may object to receiving such information by e-mail at any time. Each e-mail contains instructions on unsubscribing from future such e-mails.

As a newsletter subscriber, you will also receive a request to participate in our surveys. The survey is sent on the basis of the consent pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (1) (a) GDPR or the legitimate interest protected under Art. 6 (1) (1) (f) GDPR in conjunction with Section 7 (3) UWG. To help us constantly improve the content of our events, the information you submit within the scope of the survey is processed based on your consent. You can object to the processing of the data concerning you at any time in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR (message to: [info@dmexco.com](mailto:info@dmexco.com)).

 **Use of Hubspot**

We use an external service provider, HubSpot Email, for the technical distribution of the newsletter. HubSpot Email is a service provided by HubSpot, Inc., for managing e-mail addresses and sending messages. Hubspot is certified under the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). HubSpot processes your data exclusively on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions (and is thus what is referred to as a “processor” in accordance with Article 28 GDPR); it has also taken appropriate technical and organizational steps to protect your rights.

HubSpot uses a tracking tool to help us determine how many of you have opened our newsletters and which of the links they contain have been clicked. Technical information is collected in the course of this, such as information about your browser, the system you use and your IP address and time of retrieval. This information is used for the technical improvement of the services. The legal basis for this is Article 6 (1) (1) (f) GDPR, since we have a legitimate interest in learning user behavior as it involves the opening of our newsletters. This permits us to optimize our services and to operate the newsletter service economically as well.

Here is more information about the [privacy policy of HubSpot.](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy)  
Here is more information by [HubSpot about the EU data protection provisions.](https://legal.hubspot.com/data-privacy)

If you prefer for HubSpot not to record cookies in general, you can modify your browser settings at any time to prevent the storage of cookies or use the following opt-out link: [Hubspot Opt-Out.](mailto:privacy@hubspot.com)

### 2.8 Event calendar

As a DMEXCO exhibitor or partner, you have the opportunity to list your own events on the DMEXCO Event Calendar. These events will then appear on our website. This generates visibility for your events and makes them quicker and easier to find for partners and customers. There is no entitlement to inclusion in the Calendar.

Your personal data are processed on the basis of Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR, since your participation in this offer constitutes a license agreement.

In order to offer you this service, we process the following personal data:

  * Your status (media representative, exhibitor or neither),
  * Name,
  * E-Mail address, telephone number,
  * Contact for inquiries:

We also need the name of your company as well as a few additional details about the event and its target group. The details for this can be found in the inquiry screen.

The data you provide will not be disclosed to third parties. However, we do enlist the assistance of Hubspot for the technical implementation of the tool and the data processing associated with it.

### 2.9 Use of the Usercentrics Consent Management Platform

We use the Usercentrics Consent Management Platform to meet our legal obligation pursuant to Art. 7 (1) GDPR. The operator is Usercentrics GmbH. The Usercentrics Consent Management Platform collects log file data, user agent (device, browser type, browser language, browser version, resolution) and consent data (consent yes/no, time stamp, data scope, data attributes, ControllerID, ProcessorID, ConsentID) via a JavaScript. Usercentrics GmbH can use this JavaScript to notify the user about certain tags and web technologies on our website and to obtain, manage and document his or her consent.

The legal basis for processing these data is Art. 6 (1) (c) GDPR, as we have an obligation under law to provide proof of consent (according to Art. 7 (1) GDPR).

The goal is to know the preferences of our users and implement these accordingly, and to document them in a legally sound manner.

The data are erased as soon as they are no longer required for our logging, provided that this erasure does not conflict with legal retention obligations.

You can permanently prevent the execution of JavaScript at any time by using appropriate settings in your browser; this would also prevent Usercentrics from executing the JavaScript.

For more information on the privacy practices of Usercentrics, please visit: <https://usercentrics.com/privacy-policy/>

### 2.10 General information about cookies

We use what are known as “browser cookies” to collect information about your use of our website. These are small text files that are stored to your data medium and save specific settings and data for exchange with our system via your browser. As a rule, a cookie contains the name of the domain from which the cookie data were sent as well as information about the age of the cookie and an alphanumeric identifier. Cookies enable our systems to recognize the user’s device and make any presettings available immediately. As soon as a user accesses the platform, a cookie is transferred to the hard disk of that user’s computer.

The cookies we use have different purposes. They are used, on the one hand, to ensure security during website visits (“necessary cookies”), and on the other to implement certain features such as standard language settings (“functional cookies”), to improve the user experience or performance on the website (“performance cookies”), and for purposes of direct marketing (“targeting/advertising cookies”)

Specifically, we use the following cookies:

Cookie name | Purpose for processing | Cookie duration | Provicer

  * _ga |Traffic analysis / functional | 2 years | Google Analytics
  * _gid | Traffic analysis / functional | 24 hours | Google Analytics
  * _gat | Minimization of data traffic / functional | 1 minute | Google Analytics
  * __hstc | Traffic analysis | 13 months | Hubspot
  * hubspotutk | Traffic analysis | 24 hours | Hubspot
  * __hssc | Traffic analysis | 24 hours | Hubspot
  * pll_language |Savest he language setting / functional | 24 hours | Polylang WordPress Plugin
  * _fbp | Marketing/targeting | 24 hours | Facebook
  * lidc I Marketing/Retargeting I 24 Stunden I LinkedIn
  * ajs_anonymous_id | Video tool/functional | 1 year | Go Essential
  * ajs_user_id | Video tool/functional | 1 year | Go Essential
  * ajs_group_id | Video tool/functional | 1 year | Go Essential

The use of cookies is justified on the basis of our legitimate interest in a needs-based design, statistical evaluation of our website and an increase in advertising efficiency in accordance with Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

If you do not wish to use browser cookies, you can set your browser so that storage of cookies is not accepted. Please note that in this case you may only be able to use our website to a limited extent or not at all. If you only want to accept our own cookies, but not the cookies of our service providers and partners, you can select your browser setting to “Block third-party cookies.”

### 2.11 Tools for website analysis

We use the services of the following third parties:

 **Google Analytics with Conversion Tracking**

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”), including the Conversion Tracking feature. Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies,” text files that are stored on your device and permit analysis of your use of the website, the products you view and any purchases you make. No personal data are collected in the process. The information the cookie generates (including your truncated IP address) is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate this information, to compile reports about website activities and about products viewed or sold for the website operators, and to provide additional services relating to the website and the use of the Internet. Google may also forward this information to third parties where required by law, or where these third parties have been commissioned by Google to process these data.

For more information about how Google uses your information, please consult Google’s policy on privacy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US>

If you do not want website analysis, you can use a browser add-on to disable Google Analytics. You can download this here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en> .

The use of Google Analytics with Conversion Tracking is based on our legitimate interest in demand-oriented design, statistical evaluation and efficient promotion of our website, and the fact that your legitimate interests do not outweigh ours in this case, Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

 **Google Tag Manager**

Google Tag Manager is a solution that allows us to manage various website tags through an interface. The Tag Manager tool itself (which implements the tags) is a cookieless domain and does not collect any personal data. The tool triggers other tags, which in turn may collect data under certain circumstances. The Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If deactivation occurs at domain or cookie level, it remains in use for all tracking tags, which are implemented by Google Tag Manager.

### 2.12 Marketing and optimization tools

 **Facebook Conversion Pixel**

On this website we use what is known as the “Facebook Pixel” of the provider Facebook (for EU: Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland; International: Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA). This is a small, invisible pixel that connects to Facebook servers when you visit our website. Personal data may be transmitted in the process, such as the IP address and additional information including browser type/version, the operating system in use, the page you previously visited, the host name of the accessing device and the IP address and time of the request. This enables Facebook to identify users of our website and display advertisements targeting users with an interest in our website. In addition, we can use the Facebook Pixel to track whether our Facebook ads are effective.

Insofar as data are processed outside the EEA, where there is no level of data protection in place that satisfies the European Standard, this is done on the basis of the EU-US Privacy Shield: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC>

You will find Facebook’s privacy policy here: <https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy>.

You can object to the collection of your data by the Facebook Pixel and the use of these data here: <https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen>.

 **Twitter Pixel  
**

We also use what is known as “Conversion Tracking” with Twitter Pixel, a tool of Twitter Inc. (Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA). With Conversion Tracking, Twitter downloads a cookie to your device if you click on a Twitter ad to visit our website.

Conversion Tracking is used solely for the generation of statistics, and not to identify individuals. We simply want to be able to evaluate which Twitter ads or interactions lead users to our website. We can use this information to more effectively manage banner advertising and calculate the cost/benefit ratio accordingly.

It should be noted, however, that because Twitter data can be stored and processed, a connection to the respective user profile is possible. Further information on this can be found in the Twitter privacy statement: <http://twitter.com/privacy>.

To edit your privacy preferences and the consent you provide on Twitter, go to: <https://twitter.com/account/settings>

Use of the Twitter Pixel is in the interest of optimizing our online offerings. This represents a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

 **LinkedIn Insight Tag  
**

On our website, we use the “LinkedIn Insight Tag”. This is a conversion and retargeting tool from the LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland. It enables us to receive information about the use of our website in order to show you customized ads on LinkedIn. Furthermore, it makes it possible to create anonymous reports on the effectiveness of the advertisements and website interaction, which we receive from LinkedIn in the context of anonymous reports. A cookie is placed in your browser for this function.

The data collected is encrypted, anonymized within seven days and the anonymized data deleted within 90 days. The legal basis for the processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. In this context, our legitimate interest in an effective advertising and marketing campaign prevails.

In [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)’s privacy policy you can find more information on data collection and use, as well as your possibilities and rights for protecting your privacy.

You can deactivate LinkedIn Insight by opting out under the following link: [www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out](http://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out)

 **Hubspot**

HubSpot is another provider we use for purposes of analysis (i.e. not only for the technical distribution of our newsletters). HubSpot, a service of Hubspot Inc., is an American company with a branch in Ireland (Contact: HubSpot, 2nd Floor 30 North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland, Tel.: +353 1 5187500).

HubSpot is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield.

HubSpot uses cookies that are stored on your computer and permit us to analyze your use of the website. HubSpot evaluates the information collected (e.g. IP address, location, browser, duration of the visit, pages accessed) on behalf of this website in order to generate statistics on use of the website. These statistics are needed to ensure the smooth operation of the websites and of the offering and to continuously optimize it. The data are also used for targeted marketing.

If you generally do not want HubSpot to collect data, you can prevent the storage of cookies at any time by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. For instructions, please visit: <http://meine-cookies.org/cookies_verwalten/index.html> (only available in german language)  
If you do not wish your data to be used to display targeted advertising, you can click to unsubscribe at: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>

### 3\. Data processing in the context of further online presences

In addition to the website, we are represented on online platforms and social networks as well. If you visit these online presences and communicate with us through them, the terms and conditions and the privacy policy in effect there, as well as this Privacy Statement, will apply (as we share responsibility for this with the provider under the provisions of data protection legislation).

If you communicate with us through these online presences, we will process the data in your messages and posts based on the content contained therein, and based on the purposes pursued with the communication, on the basis of either Article 6 (1) (1) (b) GDPR or Article 6 (1) (1) (f) GDPR.

We are represented in the following online platforms:

 **Facebook (Facebook Fanpage)**

Facebook page is used for active communication with our customers and prospective customers. We use this platform to provide information about our events.

When you visit our Facebook page, your data can be automatically collected and stored for purposes of market research and advertising. These data are used, along with pseudonyms, to create what are known as “user profiles.” For this purpose, the cookies typically placed on your device store a record of visitor behavior and the user interests. Facebook provides further information on this under the following link: <https://www.facebook.com/help/pages/insights>.

Within the framework of a balancing of interests, the statistical information provided by Facebook about the use of the Facebook page (“Facebook Insights”) is used in accordance with Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR in exercise of our overriding legitimate interest in an optimized presentation of our offerings and effective communication with customers and prospective customers.

Data are processed on the basis of an agreement between joint controllers in accordance with Art. 26 GDPR. This agreement can be consulted here:  
<https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum>

Facebook has its registered office in the USA. The European Commission has passed an adequacy decision the USA. This goes back to the EU-US Privacy Shield, to which Facebook has submitted: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

You can find a link to the opt-out here: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads>

**Twitter**

You’ll find privacy information at Twitter (Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA) here: [www.twitter.com/privacy](http://www.twitter.com/privacy).  
If you would like to object to future data collection by Twitter, you can set an opt-out cookie here: <https://twitter.com/personalization>  
Insofar as data are processed outside the EEA, where there is no level of data protection in place that satisfies the European Standard, this is done on the basis of the EU-US Privacy Shield: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO>

**Xing**  
Information on data protection at Xing (Xing AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg, Germany) can be found here: <https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/printable-version>.

 **Instagram**  
Information about data protection at Instagram (Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA) and an opportunity to object can be found here: [http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875)

 **LinkedIn**  
Information on privacy at LinkedIn (LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland) can be found here: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>. If you would like to object to future data collection by LinkedIn, you can set an opt-out cookie here: <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out>  
Insofar as data are processed outside the EEA, where there is no level of data protection in place that satisfies the European Standard, this is done on the basis of the EU-US Privacy Shield: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000L0UZAA0>

**YouTube**

We integrate videos from the “YouTube” platform of provider Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Information about the privacy policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>, for the opt-out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

### 4\. SurveyMonkey

We use SurveyMonkey (SurveyMonkey Europe UC, 2nd Floor, 2 Shelbourne Buildings, Shelbourne Road, Dublin, Ireland) to conduct surveys. We conduct the surveys in order to continuously improve our range of services and the organization of events according to your feedback. That’s why your opinion is very important to us.

If you decide to participate in the survey, SurveyMonkey will collect information about your device, IP address, the version of your operating system, and information on the browser type.

As part of the survey, we query the gender, age, status and position of the participants for purely statistical purposes. We do this in order to be able to include social components in assessments of the results and to optimize them accordingly. In addition, you may voluntarily provide your first and last name as well as an e-mail address (“voluntary information”). We usually request this information when we offer a prize drawing among the participants. We need your voluntary information in order to contact you in the event that you win a prize. However, this information will be deleted once the prize drawing is completed.

The processing of your data is based on consent, Art. 6 (1) (a). Participation is on a voluntary basis.

You can contact us at any time to request erasure of your survey data, including personal data (E-Mail to info@demexco.com). Individual responses cannot be corrected after the fact once the survey has been submitted, however.

SurveyMonkey collects your information on our behalf in order to create reports with which we can analyze your satisfaction with the event offering and evaluate your suggestions.

We would like to point out that SurveyMonkey uses cookies. Information on this, as well as the duration of storage, can be found here: <https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/>

We also want to point out that SurveyMonkey usually transmits the data to a server in the USA and stores it there. You can find information about opting out of cookies here: <https://help.surveymonkey.com/articles/en_US/kb/How-do-I-enable-cookies-on-my-computer>.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus offers a guarantee of compliance with European data protection law: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000Gn7zAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000Gn7zAAC&status=Active).

### 5\. Sending news via messenger service providers

You can also order news and information about DMEXCO’s service portfolio via the “WhatsApp,” “Facebook Messenger,” “Telegram” and “Insta” messaging services via our website. We provide this service to you via MessengerPeople (MessengerPeople GmbH, Herzog-Heinrich-Str. 9, 80336 Munich, Germany).

And here’s how it works: In each case, messages are sent via an account created on our behalf with the messaging services mentioned above. So, if you sign up to send messages via WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Telegram and/or Insta via our website, MessengerPeople will receive your user name and telephone number, which you have stored with the respective messenger service.

Like registration for the newsletter, registration is via a double-opt-in procedure. You store a telephone number generated by our shipping service provider MessengerPeople (MessengerPeople GmbH, Herzog-Heinrich-Str. 9, 80336 Munich) in the address book of your smartphone and then send a start request (a message with the word “Start”) in the messenger of your choice (i.e. WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Telegram or Insta). This login process is necessary to prevent others from logging in with external data.

Registration to the messenger service is logged in order to be able to document the registration process in accordance with the legal requirements. Changes to your data stored by the shipping service provider will also be logged. Messenger People also receives information about the messages you have read and clicked as part of their service. For further details, please refer to the [privacy policy of MessengerPeople](https://www.messengerpeople.com/privacy/): <https://www.messengerpeople.com/privacy/>.

 **Here’s how to unsubscribe** : You can unsubscribe from the sending of messages by MessengerPeople at any time by sending the message “STOP” to the respective Messenger account through which you previously ordered the message service.

You can also ask MessengerPeople to erase the data at any time by sending the message “ALLE DATEN LÖSCHEN” [“DELETE ALL DATA”] to the respective Messenger account.

Distribution of the Messenger messages and the performance measurement associated with this are based on the consent pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (a), or on the legal permission pursuant to Section 7 (3) UWG.

### 6\. Disclosure of data

In principle, your personal data will only be disclosed without your express prior consent in the following cases:

  * If it is necessary to investigate unlawful use of our services or for prosecution, personal data will be passed on to law-enforcement authorities and, where appropriate, to third parties that have been harmed. This happens only when there are concrete indications of illegal or abusive conduct. We may also pass your data to third parties in order to enforce terms of use or other agreements. We are also legally obliged to provide information to certain public offices upon request. These are law enforcement agencies, authorities that pursue administrative offenses subject to fine, and tax authorities.  
These data are disclosed on the basis of our legitimate interest in combating abuse, prosecuting crimes and securing, asserting and enforcing claims, where your rights and interests in the protection of your personal data do not outweigh this interest, Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.
  * We rely on contracted third parties and external service providers (“processors”) to provide the services. In such cases, personal data will be passed on to these processors to enable them to continue processing. These processors are carefully selected and regularly reviewed by us to ensure that your privacy is respected. Processors may only use the data only for the purposes specified by us; we also place them under a contractual obligation to treat your data exclusively in accordance with this Privacy Statement and German laws on data protection.
  * As part of the further development of our business, the structure of Koelnmesse GmbH may change due to a change in the legal form, or through the establishment, acquisition or sale of subsidiaries, parts of companies or components. In such transactions, customer information is ordinarily passed along with that portion of the company that is to change hands. In any disclosure of personal data to third parties of a scope as described above, we ensure that this is done in accordance with this Privacy Statement and the relevant data protection laws.

Any disclosure of personal data is justified by the fact that we have a legitimate interest in adapting our corporate form to the economic and legal circumstances if necessary, provided that this is not outweighed by your rights and interests in the protection of your personal data, Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

### 7\. Erasure of data

We will delete or anonymize your personal data as soon as it is no longer required for the purposes for which we have collected or used it in accordance with the preceding provisions and no legal retention periods prevent its erasure, or the data is required for a longer period of time for criminal prosecution or to secure, assert or enforce legal claims.

### 8\. Your rights as a data subject

 **Right to information**

You have the right to obtain information from us at any time upon request about the personal data processed by us concerning you within the scope of Art. 15 GDPR. To do so, you can submit an application by mail or e-mail to the address shown above.

 **Right to rectify inaccurate data**

You have the right to ask us to rectify your personal data immediately if they are incorrect. To do so, please get in touch with us using the contact addresses shown above.

 **Right to erasure**

You have the right to ask us to erase personal data concerning you under the conditions described in Art. 17 GDPR. Specifically, these conditions provide for a right of erasure where the personal data are no longer necessary for the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed and in cases of unlawful processing, the existence of an objection or the existence of an obligation to erase in accordance with Union law or the law of the Member State to which we are subject. To exercise your above right, please get in touch with us at the contact addresses shown above.

 **Right to restrict processing**

You have the right to require us to restrict processing of your data in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR. This right exists in particular if the accuracy of the personal data is disputed between the user and us, for the duration that the verification of the accuracy requires and in the event that the user requires restricted processing in the case of an existing right to erasure in lieu of erasure; furthermore, in the event that the data are no longer necessary for the purposes pursued by us, but the user needs them in order to assert, exercise or defend legal claims, and if the successful exercise of an objection between us and the user is still in dispute. To exercise your above right, please get in touch with us at the contact addresses shown above.

 **Right to data portability**

You have the right to receive from us the personal data concerning you that you have provided to us in a structured, conventional and machine-readable format in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR. To exercise your above right, please get in touch with us at the contact addresses shown above.

 **Right to object**

Pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR, you have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to the processing of your personal data concerning you which is based, among other things, on Art. 6 (1) (e) or (f) GDPR. We will discontinue the processing of your personal data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

### 9\. Right to lodge a complaint

You also have the right to contact the relevant supervisory authority for data protection in the event of complaints. The supervisory authority with responsibility in the matter is:

State Officer for Data Protection and Freedom of Information  
North Rhine-Westphalia  
P.O. Box 20 04 44  
40102 Düsseldorf, Germany  
Tel.: +49 (0)211/38424-0  
Fax: +49 (0)211/38424-10  
e-mail: [poststelle@ldi.nrw.de](mailto:poststelle@ldi.nrw.de)

### 10\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

The current version of this Privacy Statement is always available under “Security and Data Protection.”

Last revised: April 2019
